cam4s.com 2018-11-03

# CAM4 Privacy Policy

####  **1\. INTRODUCTION**

Cam4 provides a peer-to-peer webcam platform service.  Your privacy and security are of paramount importance to us when you choose to use our service. Cam4 is committed to protecting the data you share with us. 

This Privacy Policy is intended to help you understand how Cam4 processes information collected through use of our website and platform that can be used to directly or indirectly identify an individual (“Personal Data”).

For the purposes of this Policy, Cam4 defines these terms:

  * “Guest” as someone who visits our front-end website (www.Cam4.com) to observe cam shows for free and without any registration,
  * “Viewer” as someone who registered an account with Cam4,
  * “Broadcaster” as a Viewer with whom Cam4 has an established relationship and who has decided to provide Cam4 with user-generated content by broadcasting webcam shows,
  * “Earners” are Broadcasters who have selected the option to earn tokens paid as tips for their performances on Cam4.

Any information stored on Cam4’s platform is treated as confidential. All data is stored securely and is accessed by authorized personnel only. Cam4 implements and maintains appropriate technical, security and organizational measures to protect all its visitors’ Personal Data against unauthorized or unlawful processing and use, and against accidental loss, destruction, damage, theft or disclosure.

####  **2\. Collection and use**

**

2.1 General

**

The following sections cover how we collect and process data for each of the four visitor groups defined above (Guests, Viewers, Broadcasters and Earners), including which pieces of data we collect and use for publication purposes, customer relations and email notifications.

**

2.2 Data from website guests

**

If you are a Guest to our website only, then this section is relevant for you.

When you visit Cam4 as a Guest, we will not ask you for any Personal Data.

However, Cam4 may collect, record, aggregate and analyze information of ALL visitors to its website, and we use analytics tracking systems such as Google Analytics to do this. Cam4 gathers data about visits to the website, including the numbers of visitors, geo-location data, length of time spent on the site, page view activity and hyperlinks clicked, where visitors have come from and what operating system is being used. We may record information from your web browser, your IP address and we use cookies to do so. 

Although such information is not personally identifiable, we use your IP address to determine your Internet Service Provider and the geographic location of your point of connectivity. We collect this sort of data to allow us to monitor and improve our site, our business and our services, and to provide you with a better user experience – for instance, by allowing us to serve you a video stream from the server nearest to you, or displaying text in your preferred language, as indicated by your browser’s language settings. 

**

2.3 Data from website viewers, broadcasters and earners

**

In order to provide additional services to its Users, Cam4 must collect more data from them, some of which is Personal Data.

If you register an account, the data we collect includes your chosen “username” and email address.

This information is used by Cam4 to identify you and provide you with support, services, mailings, sales and marketing actions, billing and to meet contractual obligations.

If you choose to fill out an optional profile to share information about yourself with Cam4 and our community of Users, the Special Category of Personal Data we collect may include your ethnicity, sexual orientation, marital status, your profile picture and your biography.

We will seek your explicit consent to process Special Category of Personal Data, collected by Cam4 or volunteered by you. Kindly note that any consent will be entirely voluntary. However, if you do not grant the requested consent to the processing of your Personal Data, the use of this website as anything other than a “Viewer” may not be possible.

Should you determine to become a “Broadcaster”, you may be asked to create a personal profile to include a name or alias you prefer to use, an email address, profile pictures, gender, date of birth, relationship status, your interests and hobbies, ethnicity and sexual orientation. We will ask you for this information in order to enable and monitor your use of our site platform and services. We will also retain snapshots of your broadcast video stream you created, and we will use that to assist us with verifying your age and to comply with law. Also, in order to comply with age verification laws and regulations, we will ask your consent to process your name, age, aliases, maiden names, nicknames, and any stage or professional names you may have used in the past or are currently using.

In the event you become an Earner, or otherwise choose to transact the purchase of goods and services through the site, one or more of our payment processors may collect billing information from you to facilitate your purchase from us. Such information may include a credit card number, its expiration date, and a billing address. WE DO NOT HAVE ACCESS TO YOUR FINANCIAL DATA, WHICH IS COLLECTED BY OUR PAYMENT PROCESSORS. Financial data that is collected by our payment processor will only be used as necessary to initiate and complete any orders placed by your account. Please see our section on Payment Service Providers for more information.

Credit card purchases on Cam4 are processed via industry standard encryption through third-party processors, and these processors will use your information only for the purpose of processing your order. The financial data you share with our processors is considered private information and will not be shared with us, or with third parties, except with your authorization and as necessary to carry out orders placed by you and with your understanding that such transaction(s) may be subject to the rules and policies of such third parties.

If there is a dispute concerning your credit card purchase, Cam4’s customer service department may receive from the relevant payment processor a truncated version of your credit card number in order to identify your purchase and to further assist or resolve the issue. We would then have in our possession a partial card number, which we would use for the proper administration of our payment services.

**

2.4 Data for customer relations

**

To properly manage our relationship with you and provide the best support and customer services, we may use your contact information including your name, your contact details, and any information found in prior communications between us. We will also keep records of our discussions so that we can follow up as needed, and to promote our products and services to you that may help address any service issues. 

**

2.5 Data for email notifications

**

When you create an account on Cam4, we may need to use your email address to notify you of important changes to your account, such as updates to Privacy Policy or Password reset requests.

If you consent to receive emails such as newsletters, product information or special offers and sales, we may use the Personal Data provided in your profile, your visitor group level, and purchase history order to tailor content and messages to your interest(s) and account type.

Many of these options can be customized in your My account > Privacy section.

**

2.6 Publications, chat and video communications

**

If you post information on our site’s platform for the purpose of publishing it we may, with your consent, process that information in the course of administering our website and services. For example, we may, with your consent, share information about languages you’ve indicated you speak so that users looking to communicate in that same language can find you more easily.

Please bear in mind that the Cam4 website features of interactive video and chat services make it possible for you to communicate identifying information about yourself to other users who are viewing a live video stream from your device. This information is given directly to those users viewing the live video stream, and not to Cam4. We cannot be responsible for the privacy of Personal Data that you communicate through video chat to users who are viewing your live video stream. Do not share Personal Data via live video streaming to other users of the Cam4 platform.

Users should be aware that making use of chat or any other means of communication via the Cam4 site could result in disclosing information that could make you personally identifiable to Cam4 or other Cam4 Users. The security and privacy protection implemented on Cam4’s platform does not cover this type of transfer or disclosure of personal information. Users alone are responsible for the content of their messaging and any consequent disclosure of Personal Data.  It is every User’s responsibility to ensure that collection and processing of data is done in accordance with applicable law. Cam4 will not process Personal Data of Users disclosed in this fashion or by other means than instructed by its Users via appropriate consents, as required by contract or law or as necessary to the functionality of the site. Please, do NOT share anyone else’s Personal Data over the Cam4 platform. 

**

2.7 Legal claims and management of risk

**

We may process any of your Personal Data identified in this Policy where it is necessary to establish, exercise or defend legal claims, either in or out of court, or to hire professional advice for the protection of our business against risk and to assert our legal rights, your legal rights and the legal rights of others.

####  **3\. Sharing of personal data**

**

3.1 General

**

The following sections tell you when and to whom Cam4 will disclose your Personal Data.

**

3.2 Legal and vital interests

**

Cam4 may disclose your Personal Data in order to obtain professional advice, to establish, exercise or defend legal claims, to comply with legal obligations or to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

**

3.3 Our companies

**

In order to accomplish the purposes set forth in this Privacy Policy, and on the legal bases set out herein, Cam4 may share your Personal Data with its group of companies and affiliated companies, including sister companies and so-called “white label” companies, and other subsidiaries of its holding company. A list of Cam4`s affiliated websites is as follows: sex.co.uk, taboocams.com, pornografia.com, pornografico.com, sexlesbian.com, lesbiansex.com, cam4bucks.com.

**

3.4 Affiliate partners

**

Cam4 has an Affiliate Program which allows partners (“Affiliates”) to earn revenue by promoting Cam4. These promotions may involve embedding profile images, live streams, chat rooms, and links to profiles on Affiliate’s websites as a means to drive traffic to Cam4 and promote our Broadcasters. 

We may disclose your publically available Personal Data, such as your profile information, profile image and live stream to our business partners and Affiliates

We may also pass information relating to your privacy settings as is reasonably necessary for the uploading, sharing and viewing of adult content, including sexually explicit images you may have added, this is also done to ensure that Affiliates who may be promoting our Broadcasters are respecting the privacy settings of the individual, such as blocked countries.

We do not share your email, name, contact or other personally identifiable information with any of these Affiliates: poringa.net and jizz.xxx.

**

3.5 Payment services providers

**

We will share transaction data with our payment services providers only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing your payments, refunding such payments and handling complaints and questions. For more information about our payment processors privacy policies and practices, visit their website: [Epoch Payment Solutions](https://epoch.com/privacy.html), [Segpay Corp.](https://www.segpay.com/privacy.html), DialXS

**

3.6 3rd party providers of goods/services

**

A service provider (SP) provides organizations with consulting, legal, real estate, communications, storage, processing, etc. Although a service provider can be an organizational sub-unit, it is usually a third party or outsourced supplier, including financial service providers (banks or payment processors), telecommunications service providers, application service providers, storage service providers, internet service providers, etc.

We may disclose some of your Personal Data (but none of the categories of special personal data) to one or more of our third party suppliers of services (for example to the banks in order to pay your earnings from your broadcasts) so that they can accomplish their duty to give you their best possible service.

**

3.7 Our legal obligation to disclose personal data

**

We will reveal a User’s Personal Data without prior permission when we have reason to believe that the disclosure of this information is required to establish the identity of, to contact or to initiate legal proceedings against, a person or persons who are suspected of infringing rights or property belonging to Cam4 or to others who could be harmed by the User’s activities. We are permitted to disclose personal information when we have good reason to believe that this is legally required.

Government authorities may, without your consent (or our consent), communicate information to other authorities, including relevant police if there is reasonable cause to believe that a criminal or penal offense has been committed or is about to be committed.

####  **4\. Special categories of personal data**

Special Categories of Personal Data are defined as Personal Data revealing:

  * racial or ethnic origin
  * political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs
  * trade union membership
  * biometric data for the purpose of uniquely identifying a natural person
  * data concerning health
  * data concerning a natural person’s sex life or sexual orientation

If you choose to fill out an optional profile to share information about yourself with Cam4 and our community of Users, the Special Category of Personal Data we collect may include your ethnicity, sexual orientation, marital status, your profile picture and your biography. 

Should you consent to such use, and never without your consent, this information is used by Cam4 to identify you and provide you with the best possible user experience, support, and services. For instance, helping you find cams and users who share the same interests, identifying you to other users, and preventing advertisers from showing you content you are not interested in. We also use this Personal Data to improve our marketing messages and campaigns to be relevant to your interest and experiences.

While users often share other types of Special Categories of Personal Data in personal biographies and profiles, such as political opinions or philosophical beliefs, Cam4 does not use this information for any purpose but retains it for you as part of our website services. You are of course free to edit, modify, delete and share your own personal information in your profiles, as long as it is compliant with law and our Terms of Service.

####  **5\. International transfers of personal data**

**

5.1 Operations

**

The Cam4 platform is supported by a network of computers, cloud-based servers, and other information technologies including 3rd party service providers. Some of these services may come from jurisdictions other than your own, and those countries do not always afford an equivalent level of privacy protection. We have taken strict measures to protect your Personal Data; in particular, we rely on your explicit consent and security and confidentiality of your Personal Data in binding corporate rules and contractual protections. We are required to transfer your Personal Data with those parties in order to be able to provide the requested service to you. 

**

5.2 Acknowledgement

**

You acknowledge that Personal Data you submit for publication or broadcast using our platform services may be available via the Internet, worldwide, and we cannot prevent the use or misuse of such Personal Data by others.

####  **6\. Retention and deletion**

Cam4 will not retain data longer than is necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected or as required by applicable laws or regulations. Cam4’s Users have control over the purpose for collecting data, and the duration for which the Personal Data may be kept. Users with an active account will therefore have the responsibility to delete data when required. When a User’s account is terminated or expired, all Personal Data collected through the platform will be deleted, as required by applicable law, with the exception that we may retain your Personal Data where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

Cam4 Users can at any time access and edit, update or delete their contact details by logging in with their username and password to Cam4’s platform.

####  **7\. Your privacy rights by law and per this privacy policy**

**

7.1 The rights to access

**

You have the right to know whether or not we process your Personal Data and you have the right to access it along with certain additional information. That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of Personal Data concerned and who has received it. Providing the rights of others are not affected, we will supply to you a copy of your Personal Data, at no charge. Additional copies are subject to a reasonable fee. You can access your Personal Data from inside your account details on our site.

**

7.2 The rights to rectification

**

You have the right to have any inaccurate Personal Data about you rectified and, taking into account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete Personal Data about you completed.

**

7.3 The right to erasure

**

In some circumstances, you have the right to have us erase your personal data without undue delay. Those circumstances include: your Personal Data is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing purposes; and if the Personal Data has been unlawfully processed. However, there are exclusions of the right to erasure. The general exclusions include where processing is necessary for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information; for compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

**

7.4 The right to restrict processing

**

If you contest the accuracy of your Personal Data or if processing is unlawful but you oppose erasure; or if we no longer need the Personal Data for the purposes of our processing but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims; or if you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection, then you may restrict the processing of your Personal Data. However, in that event, we may continue to store your Personal Data and we will only process it with your consent or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims or for the protection of the rights of another natural person, or for reasons of important public interest.

**

7.5 The right to object to processing

**

You have the right to object to our processing of your Personal Data for direct marketing purposes (including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your Personal Data for this purpose.

**

7.6 The right to data portability

**

If our legal basis for processing your Personal Data is consent; or that the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract, and such processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your Personal Data from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights of others.

**

7.7 The right to complain to a supervisory authority

**

If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you may have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. If you are a EU citizen, you have the right to do so in the EU member state of your residence, your place of work or the place of the infringement.

**

7.8 The right to withdraw consent

**

If the legal basis for our processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of processing before the withdrawal.

**

You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by contact us at https://www.cam4.com/contact, in addition to the other methods specified in this section.

**

####  **8\. Cookies**

Cam4 places cookies to store and then retrieve small bits of information on your computer when you visit. This is to ensure that our content is tailored to your specifications, thereby improving the visitor experience of the site. More details about how we use cookies you can find on Cookies Policy.

####  **9\. Acceptance of these conditions**

We assume that all Visitors to Cam4’s platform have carefully read this document and agree to its contents. If you do not agree with this Privacy policy, you should refrain from using our website and platform. We reserve the right to change our Privacy Policy as necessity dictates. Continued use of the Cam4 website and platform after having been informed of any such changes to these conditions implies acceptance of the revised Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is an integral part of Cam4’s Terms of Use.

####  **10\. Our details**

**

10.1 Owner

**

This website is owned and operated by Granity Entertainment DAC, an Irish company duly incorporated in Dublin, Ireland under Registration Number 525757 and principally located at 23 Seafield Road, Blackrock, County Dublin, Ireland.

**

10.2 Contact information

**

If you have any further questions regarding the data Cam4 collects, or how we use it, then please feel free to contact us:

By Post To: Granity Entertainment DAC 23 Seafield Road, Blackrock, County Dublin, Ireland

General email contact: contact@cam4.com

Data Protection Officer email contact: dpo@cam4.com
